（記者）棋匠(きしょう)　柳原(やなぎはら)棋匠
Shogi Maestro... Shogi Maestro Yanagihara...
（記者）いつまで
Ａ級でいられると思いますか？
How long do you think you can remain in Class A?
Ａ級から落ちたら
引退を考えますか？
Would you think about retiring if you were demoted from Class A?
若手の台頭をどう思われますか？
What do you think about the up-and-coming youngsters?
（がんちゃん）怖(こえ)えなぁ
I'm scared.
Without my work,
俺から仕事を取ったら
何が残ってんだ？
what's left for me?
（がんちゃん）怖えよ 朔(さく)ちゃん
I'm scared, Saku.
（柳原）そうだな がんちゃん
I hear you, Gan.
俺も ずっと同じこと考えてる
I'm always thinking the same thing.
でも まだ答えは出てねえんだ
But I still don't have an answer.
ただ お前が立っているのが—
However, if you're standing
焼け野原なのだとしたら…
in a burnt field,
俺は まだ焼かれている真っ最中だ
then I'm still burning.
さて いこうか
Well, shall we go?
勝つことも—
Winning,
そして—
and even losing,
負けることすら いつだって…
そうは簡単に
決まっちゃくれないもんなんだ
aren't things that can ever be decided so easily.
今日も また 火だるまになって…
I'll become a human torch again today
存分に苦しんでやろうじゃないか
and give full rein to my suffering.
Among the freshly blooming dandelions
And the droplets of water which couldn't quite become snow
I thought I could make out a face stained with tears
So I offered my umbrella without a second thought
Is going left or right correct?
The path ended before I could really decide
But surely the right call is the one which spares that special someone
From any painful experiences
So with a little courage, take that plunge forward
If everything's all crooked, take an oblique path
As long as you're moving forward, you'll find the light
Like those little birds that huddle together and cry out in unison
We'll definitely ring in the start of a new season
And so spring will embrace us once more
We'll splash paint on some new pages
We became fast friends, we enjoyed some good food
We might've even argued a little
But we carry those little moments in our hearts
As reasons which compel us toward a future that can't possibly be mistaken
No matter how many times we find ourselves lost among sunlit trees
Today has been carried here by the winds on a one-way ticket
That blooms into a perfect day
Burnt Field (Part 3)
（駒を打つ音）
（島田(しまだ)）あっ…
（島田）１二銀…
S*1b?
（二海堂(にかいどう)）えっ…　角は？
What about the bishop?
（零(れい)）アア…
The bishop isn't going to escape?
（二海堂）角は逃げないのか？
ハッ…　そうか
I see!
Lance
That's not it.
違う
Yanagihara is looking beyond that.
柳原さんが見ているのは
この先の…
（島田）２五香だ
It's L*2e.
打たれたら 受けるすべが…
If he drops it there, I can't...
defend!
ない…
（島田）強い…
He's good.
なにが現役最年長だ
Eldest active player, my ass!
There's no way.
ウソだろう…
何だよ？　このでたらめな強さは
He can't be this good.
What should I do?
どうしたらいい？
What should I...
どうしたら…
（零）来た！　２五香
（二海堂）兄者　どうする？
There it is.
L*2e!
Big Brother, what will you do?
Please!
南無(なむ)…
B*1d!
１四角！
He defended with the bishop he just captured?
（二海堂）
今 取ったばかりの角で受けた！
But this is...
（二海堂）あっ でも これって…
（零）いや でも…
Yeah, but...
確かに…
It's certainly...
Was that the right move?
良かったのか？　いや だが—
But my only defense for the pawn at 2c was dropping this bishop.
２三の地点を受けるには
この角打ちしか…
He dropped the bishop right away.
（柳原）
とっさに角を打ってきやがった
だが しかし…
However,
いい判断だ
it was a wise decision.
（後藤(ごとう)）フッ…　島田なんて—
I'm sure if you leave Shimada alone, he'll just start winning again.
どうせ放っときゃ
勝手に また勝ちだすさ
そうだな 後藤
お前の言うとおりだ
That's right, Gotou.
It's just as you said.
Plainly, steadily,
地味に 地道に—
and arduously he built himself up,
コツコツ 自分を積み上げて—
and then he came back, one layer thicker.
また一枚 分厚くなって
戻ってきたよ
Yes, he must be...
こいつは そうだ
ケヤキの木だ
a zelkova tree.
It takes a long time for them to grow big,
ゆっくりとしか
大きくなれねえ代わりに—
雨風に耐え 堅くて でかい木に育つ
but they're resistant to wind and rain,
and they eventually become huge, tough trees.
ならば 俺は？
Then what am I?
If I had to compare myself to something,
俺は 例えるなら…
何であったんだろう？
what would I be?
そうだな　分からねえな
Yeah.
I just don't know.
例えてくれる先人も—
I don't have a single predecessor left
もはや ただのひとりも なし
who would compare me to something.
（柳原）あれ？　ちくしょう
Huh? Crap.
I can't let my mind drift in the middle of a match.
いかんな　対局中に
頭ん中で余計なことをつらつらと…
アア…　腰が痛(いて)えな
目も かすんできた
Man, my back hurts.
And my vision is starting to blur.
いや それでも
いつもよりは ずっと体調はいい
But still, I feel much better than usual.
１局目なんて ひどかったもんな
I felt terrible during our first match.
They called it "elderly pneumonia."
老人性肺炎って…　死ぬかと思った
I thought I was going to die.
I'm surprised I won that one.
よく まあ あれで勝てたもんだよ
Whoops, he's glaring at me.
おっと いかん…　にらまれた
お〜 怖い怖い
How scary.
There's no need to make that kind of face.
そんな顔しなくても　フッ…
今 お前が優勢だよ
You've got the advantage right now.
お前のほうが
The match is leaning your way.
I see.
そうか　俺は…
So am I...
going to lose?
負けるのか
ず〜っと考えてた
I thought about it all this time.
俺から将棋を取ったら
何が残るんだろう？
If shogi is taken away from me, what would be left?
Shimada Kai, 8-dan, has defended against Shogi Maestro Yanagihara's attacks, which started with L*2e.
（司会）
２五香からの柳原棋匠の攻めを—
ここまで受けきった島田開(かい)八段
ここで優勢に転じました
Now, the advantage has been reversed.
Will he finally attain his first title?
ついに念願の初タイトルなるか？
対する柳原棋匠
Meanwhile, Shogi Maestro Yanagihara seems more fatigued as Shimada, 8-dan, puts pressure on him.
島田八段の追い上げに
疲労の色が濃くなってきたか？
It looks like he's struggling and can't concentrate.
集中できず
苦戦しているようにも感じられます
Shogi Maestro Yanagihara is close to the Eternal Shogi Maestro title, which requires winning it ten times,
柳原棋匠　棋匠戦通算10期による
永世棋匠には—
but can he take the final step?
あと１歩 手が届かないか？
Saku, is this as far as you go?
（男性）朔ちゃん　ここまでか？
Just one more! You just need one more win!
（男性）
あと… あと１勝だったのに
No, you did great, Saku.
（男性）いや 朔ちゃん 頑張ったよ
In fact, you did great making it this far!
（男性）むしろ
よくぞ ここまで頑張ってくれた
I'm going to retire.
（棋士Ａ）俺 引退するよ
（棋士Ｂ）
朔ちゃん　俺 降級が決まった
Saku, I'm... being demoted.
It's frustrating, but I'm going to look for another path.
悔しいけれど 別の道を探すよ
（棋士Ｃ）朔ちゃん　ダメだ
俺は もう潮時と観念したよ
Saku, it's over for me.
I've accepted that this is the right time.
Saku, I'm moving back to the countryside.
（棋士Ｄ）朔ちゃん
俺 田舎に帰ることにしたよ
（がんちゃん）
怖えなぁ　怖えよ 朔ちゃん
I'm scared.
I'm scared, Saku.
まるで—
I feel like...
I'm in a burnt field.
焼け野っ原にいるみてえだ
No!
（柳原）ダメだ…
分からんが これは…
I don't know why,
but I'm not supposed to...
俺が絶対に手放しちゃ…
いけねえもんだ！
let go of this!
俺が担いで届けるものだ
I'll shoulder this burden and deliver it!
精いっぱい頑張った人間が
最後に たどりつく場所が…
So that the people who tried with all their might can arrive at a place...
that isn't some burnt field!
焼け野が原なんかで
あってたまるものか！
（島田）１七玉…
K-1g?
玉を上がるだと？
He's moving his king up?
K-1f?!
１六玉？
聞いたことないよ １六玉って
I've never heard of anyone doing that!
A Climbing King?
（二海堂）棒玉(ぼうぎょく)？
（零）どういうこと？
What is this?
C-Can he even do that?
（二海堂）そ… そんな手ありかよ
（零）あっ でも…
Yeah, but...
Saku!
（男性たち）朔ちゃん
（男性）朔ちゃん　頑張れ
Saku, you can do it!
確かに…
True.
とがめる手がない
I have no move to rebuke that.
じじい…
Damn you, old man...
You're too old to be making that move.
若々しすぎるだろう その手はよ
With time,
（柳原）時がたてば—
焼け野っ原には イヤでも また
あっという間に草が生える
grass will grow again on a burnt field,
whether we like it or not.
It'll become a field of green.
一面の緑になる
それを一緒に…
And we'll see it...
見るんだよ！
together!
Burnt Field (Part 3)
Burnt Field (Part 4)
（零）
限界をとうに超えているのは—
He'd gone far beyond his limits.
見ているだけでも分かった
Anyone watching could see that.
泥のように重たげな体を
脇息(きょうそく)に預け—
His body leaned heavily on the armrest,
ただ のめるように盤を見つめる
just staring at the board as if he were going to fall forward.
But each move those quivering fingers sent out...
けれど その震える指から
繰り出される一手一手は…
ゆっくりと
あふれ出す溶岩流のように—
was like slowly flowing lava—
重く 赤く…
heavy, red,
煌々(こうこう)と輝いていた
and glowing brilliantly.
激闘だった
It was a fierce battle.
棋士ならば 誰もが…
Any pro shogi player...
would sincerely say...
“こんな将棋を指してみたい”と…
心の底から…
that they've always wanted to play...
思わずにいられないような
a match like this.
Shogi
Hall
（零）そして…
And then...
169手にもわたった大激闘は…
after a heated battle that lasted 169 moves,
島田さんの
振り絞るような ひと言で…
it took all of Shimada's strength to utter two words
幕を下ろした
that brought it to an end.
（司会）以上 169手をもちまして
先手 柳原棋匠の勝ち
After 169 moves, the winner is Shogi Maestro Yanagihara.
棋匠戦の規定により—
By the rules of the Shogi Maestro Tournament, since he retained the title ten times,
通算10期達成のため
永世棋匠 獲得となります
he receives the title "Eternal Shogi Maestro."
（歓声）
朔ちゃん やった！　通算10期！
Saku, you did it! Ten wins!
（男性）オオーッ！　やった！
永世 取ったぞ！
He did it! He's the Eternal Shogi Maestro!
Yeah!
（男性）やったー！
（拍手）
Mr. Yanagihara, are you okay?
（スタッフ）
柳原先生　大丈夫ですか？
（柳原）ああ…　大丈夫
I'm fine.
ハハッ…
ちょっと膝が笑っちまって
My knees just gave way.
ありがとう
Thank you.
Shogi Maestro Tournament
Match Five
（男性）朔ちゃん！
（歓声）
Saku!
（零）柳原棋匠
Shogi Maestro Yanagihara...
Wh-What about the post-match review?
か… 感想戦は？
Mr. Yanagihara!
（男性）
柳原先生！　わあ！　おめでとう！
Wow! Congratulations!
（男性）朔ちゃん！
Saku!
That was awesome! That shogi was awesome!
（男性）
すげえよ！　すげえ将棋だったよ！
がんちゃん！
Gan!
H-Huh?
え… えっ？　俺か？
な… 何だよ？　朔ちゃん
Me?
What is it, Saku?
（柳原）撮ってくれよ
（がんちゃん）はぁ？
Take a photo!
What?
You brought your camera, right?
持ってきてんだろう？　カメラ
撮ってくれよ
Take a photo!
With everyone here!
ここにいる み〜んなでさ
（二海堂）あっ…
あっ ちょっと待ってください
O-Oh, wait a second!
Maybe someone should hold this to commemorate it.
The 33rd
Shogi maestro Tournament
M
Fifth match
これ持つと記念になるかも
Good thinking, kiddo.
（柳原）
おお 坊！　頭いいな　こっち来い
Come on over.
（二海堂）は… はい！
R-Right!
（柳原）よっこいしょっと…
（二海堂）ハァ〜ッ…　隣だぁ
And, there.
Wow, I'm right next to him!
Well, I guess I'll go here.
（立会人）
よっと…　俺 ここでいいかな？
立会人だもんな
I am the observer, after all.
（男性）２列目は ここに座るか
Should the second row sit here?
Tanabe! Get behind Saku!
（男性）田辺(たなべ)さん
朔ちゃんの後ろに入んなよ
What the hell? I can't fit everyone in when you're milling about.
なんだよ
入んねえよ こんなゾロゾロ
Scoot in closer.
もっと左右 詰めて！
（男性）広角とかねえの？
Don't you have a wide-angle lens?
What's it matter, as long as you fit?
（がんちゃん）入りゃ
いいってもんじゃねえだろうが
Hey, Gan! You're getting in here too!
（柳原）…つうか がんちゃん
お前も入るんだぞ　タイマー使えよ
Use a self-timer!
あっ 来た来た
Oh, there he is!
島田も
Shimada, you too!
Would you be in the photo?
頼む　入ってくれねえか？
記念撮影？　俺も？
A commemorative photo?
You want me in it?
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Yanagihara
merch
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
ハァ…　おんちゃんたち
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Didn't you guys come here to support me?
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
俺のこと応援しに来て
くれてたんじゃないの？
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
Gleaming
Lively
Glossy
We can't help it, Kai!
（男性）しかたねえべ 開
Glossy
Mr. Yanagihara is a hero to our generation!
柳原先生は
俺たち同世代のヒーローなんだべさ
Glossy
He was so cool!
（男性）いやぁ かっこえがった
What?
（男性）柳原先生が
こげに頑張ってんだから—
Mr. Yanagihara is still working hard,
so we can't be put out to pasture either!
俺たちも まだまだ頑張らねばな
That's right!
Maybe I'll plant more hostas and angelica trees in my greenhouse.
（男性）ハウスのウルイとタラの芽
もう少し増やすべか
Yeah, maybe I'll grow more garlic chives and scallions next year!
（男性）俺も 来年のニラとネギ
作付け増やすべかな
（男性）もう出稼ぎは出らんねども
ハウスなら少しは冬も稼げるべ
I can't travel for work anymore, but I can make
some money from the greenhouse in the winter.
After all, I still want to give the grandkids some pocket money.
まんだまんだ 孫に小遣いとかは
やりてえもんな
Hold on!
（神宮寺(じんぐうじ)）ちょっと待った！
朔ちゃん！　俺 俺　俺も入れて！
Saku! Get me in the photo too!
もちろん朔ちゃんの隣に！
Of course,
right next to you!
What the hell? The match is already over!
なんだよ！　もう対局終わったよ
Bastard. You just came to drink.
この野郎
酒だけ飲みに来やがったな
No, Saku.
違(ちげ)えよ 朔ちゃん
ハァ …たく もう ボケてんだから
Sheesh, you're going senile.
ンッ…
えっ？　じゃ 何だってんだよ？
Huh?
Then what's going on?
You're the one who said, "Toku, I always lose when you come to watch, so stay away!"
“徳(とく)ちゃんが見に来ると
いっつも負けるから—”
“絶対に来んな”って言ったの
朔ちゃんだろうが
（柳原）
えっ？　あれ？　そうだっけ？
Huh? Did I say that?
（笑い声）
（男性）ひでえ！
That's awful!
Okay, okay!
はい ほら！　騒いでねえで撮るぞ
Quit making a fuss! I'm taking the shot!
All right, all right!
分かった分かった
みんな　し〜っ…
Shush, everyone!
Put on a smile!
（がんちゃん）いい顔しろよ
はい シャッターまで10秒！
Okay, ten seconds!
Ten, nine...
10，９…
（柳原）“さよならだけが人生だ”
Life is nothing but goodbyes.
Who said that again?
誰が言ったんだっけ？
せいせいとしたいい言葉だ
It's a good, accurate expression.
１人ずつ欠けていくことも
分かってる
I know I'm going to lose them one by one.
From shogi and from life.
将棋からも 人生からも
But I remember.
でもな 俺は覚えている
好きなヤツも 嫌いなヤツも
山ほどいたが
There were a lot of people I liked, and a lot of people I disliked.
間違いねえ
There's no mistake.
Who I am now is made up of all those fragments.
今の俺は
その全部のカケラでできている
タスキってのは“期待”だ
These sashes represent hope.
I'm bearing hundreds—even thousands—of them now,
何百何千とかけられた それは—
時に 身動きさえ取れぬほど
重いものであったが
and sometimes they're so heavy that I can't even move,
but because of that weight,
火だるまになる恐怖からも…
重く…
and because they're bound so tightly,
逃げ出せぬように
縛りつけてくれていた
it won't let me run away from my fear of becoming a human torch.
皮肉なもんだな
It's ironic.
（柳原）
だとしたら 俺は ひょっとして—
Then I guess I could also say that thanks to that "weight," I made it this far without running away.
この重さのおかげで ここまで
逃げずに来られたとも言えるのか
But I won't say thanks!
いや！　でも 礼なんぞ言わんぞ！
Rage
Because I'm serious and passionate every time!
毎回
本気で熱いんだからな！
Every single time, I think,
"This time I'll seriously die for sure!" Damn it!
毎回毎回 〝今回こそ
マジで死ぬ〞って—
本気で思うんだからな
こんちくしょう！
Huh? Wh-What?
ええっ！　なな… なに？
They foist their dreams on me!
（柳原）
勝手に 他人に夢 託しやがって
お前ら 安全圏から—
They sit on the sidelines and go, "Hang in there," or "Keep your head in the match," or "Be grateful you can still play"!
“もっと頑張れ”だの
“もっと しっかりやれ”だの—
“感謝して指せ”だの
言われなくても頑張っとるわ 毎回
I'm already doing my best every single time!
I don't need to be told!
（神宮寺）
だから 何のことさ？　泣いてるし
What the hell are you going on about?
And you're even crying.
（柳原）ハァ…　しかし…
Still...
Next year is probably out of the question.
来年は もうムリだろうな
あっ いやいや…
まだまだ分からんよ
Oh, sorry.
But it's too early to say that.
What?
（柳原）な… なに？
今 笑ったな！　ええ？
You just laughed at me, didn't you?!
なんでよ？　ムリだろうがよ
And of course I can't do it!
俺 死ぬぜ
今日みたいな対局 来年もやったら
I'll die if I play another match like today's!
You're still gonna push me?!
まだ頑張らせる気かよ
Have a heart! I'm almost 60!
ちょっと待ってよ　還暦前なんだぜ
あのな
Listen.
さっきのセリフ
去年も言ってたから
You said the same thing to me last year.
Oh, did I?
（柳原）えっ？　そうだっけ？
（神宮寺）ああ 言ってた
You sure did.
And we're both way past 60.
あと 俺たち
還暦 とっくにオーバーしてるから
（柳原）ええっ？
（神宮寺）次 古希だから
Really?
We've got our 70th birthday coming up.
What?!
Burnt Field (Part 4)
Surrounded by a landscape on the verge of permanent stasis
I found myself searching for something
I took up a mask to make my pitifully weak self appear stable
And donned it boldly
The sound of my frozen footsteps as I walked along the river
Was easily overpowered by the roar of a passing train
Yet I kept chanting "I just gotta take another step" to myself
Over and over again
Can you hear me proclaiming that I'm standing right here?
Even in bare feet I can go wherever the hell I want
I don't know where I might find myself at the end
I can't begin to guess, but I can just ink in
A new landscape to suit me as I go
Next Episode Preview
Episode 41
（あかり）
はい 出来上がり！
ご覧あれ！
They're done!
Voila!
Yum!
It's so chewy!
（モモ）
モキュモキュしてる！
Good idea! Let's ask him!
（あかり）名案！
お願いしよう！
That plum syrup was made by Chiho.
（ひなた）これは
ちほちゃんが—
作ってくれた
梅シロップなんだ
That's a nice smell from the plums.
（相米二(そめじ)）
いい梅の香りだ
Illustration: Ikuemi Ryou
（神宮寺）
朔ちゃん　おめでとう！
Saku, congratulations!
You really do win when I'm not there.
本当に俺がいないと
勝てるんだな…